I've got orders from the mill.
To my luck, I have no people
to help cut down the sugarcanes.
If you know anyone,
please send them my way.
Sure, I'll see to it.
[phone rings]
- Hello, sir?
- [in Malayalam] You called, Selvi?
Yes, sir. I'll work for you.
- Over here?
- Yes, sir.
- Hop on the Tuesday train, then.
- No, I'm coming right away.
I'll hang up, sir.
[phone rings]
Who's going at this hour?
Answer me!
Brother Mani, it's me!
- Selvi.
- Ah, Selvi!
- What are you doing all alone?
- I…
We're on a pilgrimage walk
to Melmaruvathur.
- They're waiting for me at Kalarikuppam.
- Stay safe, then.
Watch your step.
Ah, a bus…
Wait! Stop!
Stop! Please!
Stop for me, please!
Please!
Oh, look!
What an eye candy at this hour?!
Careful, this must be
a honey-trap like situation.
- Don't stop. Keep moving.
- Hello!
Please stop!
[group singing a devotional song]
Lord Ayyanar, save me!
NOORU SAMI
I’ve got to start work
from tomorrow, Uncle.
Now that their dad's no more,
they'll now have to endure
my torture.
If you could be with the children
till they grow up,
I can take good care of you all.
We don’t want to depend on you
more than we already do.
Why don't you ask your parents?
The well at Melakadu dried up, Selvi.
I must get it up and running
to water the fields.
I can't abandon it all now,
just to be with you, dear.
- The saltfish's for you!
- Selvi,
I can't look after it
all by myself.
Let Dad be with me.
Take Mom with you.
Here, have some more curry.
Enough for me.
Selvi…
Why don't you build a makeshift
place near us?
- Granny, feed me!
- Eat, dear.
Like Dad's bothered about his fields,
and you leaving him,
I'm worried about my kids
and their education.
- Hey…
- Come along, boys!
- Selvi, wait!
- Hear me out, my child.
- Don't go.
- Bye-bye, all of you!
- Come.
- Such a stubborn girl I have!
Here you go.
Your children's future is now
a priority, Selvi.
If they join us this year,
they can study for free
until they graduate.
- Go on. Eat up, you two.
- Why can't we study here?
- How dare you to toss your plate away!
- Mom, please!
- Don't you ever do that!
- Mom, I'm sorry! Please don't hit me!
It's for your own good!
That's final.
You are going. Is that clear?
Clear?
You're going with him, too.
Selvi?
Selvi, please don't!
Don't make a fuss now, Vivek.
Let… let go of my hands!
Grab his suitcase, Baskar!
- Please, don't send us!
- Vivek!
Throw all the tantrums you want!
You’re still going.
Catch hold of him, Baskar.
Do you want to get it good
like yesterday?
Don't make me hit you too, Baskar.
- Ma'am, can you hold him down?
- I'll take care of him.
You'll be fine. Trust me.
Why are you at my feet?
See, there are many kids
like you inside.
Listen, you'll be fine.
Stop crying for nothing!
Stop whining and get in, Baskar!
[both] Mom! Mom!
Please don't send us away!
Please!
Let us stay here and study!
See?
Kids your age are so quiet.
You'll make many friends!
Please stop crying.
- Mom! Mom, please!
- Take us with you, please!
Let us stay with you, Mom!
Don't send us away, Mom! Please!
- Mom, they're starting the bus!
- Please, please, take us with you!
[both] Mom! Mom! Mom!
- Don't go away, please!
- Mom! Mom!
My babies!
♪ Even if all the gods appear
Even if they stand so near ♪
♪ Mother stands above them all ♪
♪ Even if sky and earth unite
Even if they fill our sight ♪
♪ Mother stands above them all ♪
♪ Sometimes a flame
Sometimes a calm shade ♪
♪ She shifts for your sake ♪
♪ Even in struggle
Even in hunger ♪
♪ She gives all she has ♪
♪ When the world stands in our way
When even our own say no ♪
♪ She stands with us still ♪
♪ She becomes the burning wick
Her dreams become the fire ♪
♪ She shines as our guiding light ♪
♪ Mother’s love… ♪
♪ A love so pure ♪
♪ No need for words to say
Love is felt in every way ♪
♪ Mother holds it all inside
My eyes won’t ever hide ♪
♪ No need for words to say
Love is felt in every way ♪
♪ Mother holds it all inside
My eyes won’t ever hide ♪
Look at this!
That's Oman's currency.
Bas, it's Singapore's.
- Hush now and study.
- Look at Australia's!
- Sir, your passport.
- Please be on time for your flight.
Brother…
Give it to Sir.
I'll take it from him.
Please take it from her, sir.
- Here you go.
- Thank you!
See you.
Don’t take this the wrong way,
but from tomorrow,
please wear a bindi
when you come in.
♪ At first sight,
Her eyes would cry ♪
♪ At my first words,
Her face lit joy ♪
♪ When I slip,
She sets me straight ♪
♪ She fixes my flaws
Makes me great ♪
♪ For our dreams to rise… ♪
♪ For our dreams to rise
She waits with hopeful eyes ♪
♪ Who like a mother walks this earth? ♪
♪ She bears pain we'll never know ♪
♪ She’s the root from which we grow ♪
It's for my kids' education.
I can't lend you that much.
- Please leave!
- Sir, please!
I can't decide this alone. I'll discuss
with the other three partners.
♪…all inside
My eyes won’t ever hide ♪
♪ No need for words to say
Love is felt in every way ♪
♪ Mother holds it all inside
My eyes won’t ever hide ♪
I endured through things
I can’t bring myself to tell my kids,
because they were with me.
[door knocks]
Selvi? Selvi!
Slept already?
Can you come to the backyard?
I'll write you up an acre in return!
Selvi? Hey, Sel!
Give me your number.
I've written mine on your window.
Call me when you can.
Selvi?
I heard you asked the financier for money
for your sons' education.
You could've come to me, first!
We're all going to die anyway.
So, let's live the night to the fullest!
Is there any place in this world
where a woman living alone
is treated with dignity and respect?
PUBERTY CEREMONY
C. VANATHI (A) CHITTU
Stand at the front, Vivek.
Bas, smear some
turmeric paste on her.
Baskar…
- You must do it.
- Do it properly!
- That's enough.
- This guy…
- Look at them blush!
- Aw, look how shy they are!
Baskar, how are you doing?
Yeah, I'm alright.
- Seems like you got here last night?
- No, I just got here.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
I noticed your light
was still on past 11.
So I assumed
you got on the last bus here.
- Baskar!
- Excuse me…
Something's fishy, Driver.
Why would you talk to him?
Like I wanted to.
- How are you doing, Selvi?
- Uh… I'm well.
I've been getting a lot of
alliances from IT--
The nerve of you
to bring up alliances here!
- Get me that mic!
- On it.
Here you go.
Listen up, everybody!
You too, broker.
I have three sisters.
Since Selvi's the only sibling
with two sons,
one of them will definitely
be my son-in-law.
If anyone comes to her,
asking for their hands in marriage,
I will murder them.
I say this with all due respect.
Thank you for listening.
What's wrong with Uncle, Mom?
Hey, ask her where she went.
Why meddle in others’ affairs
when you’ve got your own?
- Selvi, um…
- Yeah?
- Getting back from Sankarapuram, is it?
- Yeah.
I tried to apply for a widow pension.
But the broker wants a 10,000 bribe.
Ten thousand!
Such thievery!
The gall of robbing the poor.
If that tiny pension
is all they have to depend on,
why not pay it up front
and get it over with?
What makes you think
I’ll depend only on that?
Can't a woman like me remarry?
Like I want to die alone
in the end.
Loser.
Selvi?
- Oh, Sir! Come in.
- Selvi.
Can you please stitch
the flag corners?
- Sure, sir. I'll--
- Actually…
You can give it to me tomorrow.
Okay, sir.
Selvi…
Yes, sir?
You…
Do you really…
Do you really want to
get married again?
Did you hear me talking
to Pachaperumal?
No!
I'm just curious.
Sir…
I’ve loved having mehendi stains
on my hands since I was a child.
I also love bindis.
But now… I'm not supposed to
like any of these.
Because…
I'm a widow.
I can go to the grove
only when Vimala wants to pee.
If I go alone, people will talk.
Rats run all night.
If I switch on the lights to catch them,
people question why a house
without a man needs lights at night.
I feel… like I'm in a prison.
Even if I had killed my husband,
it'll only be 10 or 12 years in prison.
But my husband died
because of his ill fate,
and I'm imprisoned for life.
If one slipper is torn,
the other one is also punished.
To throw me out
on the road like that…
Am I just a slipper?
My life…
I can’t accept that
it has ended halfway like this.
Like everyone,
I, too, add salt to my food.
Just like them…
I, too…
want to live a happy life.
Why are you laughing?
Do I look disgusting now?
Oh, no!
If someone had asked me
if I wanted to remarry,
I'd just say 'yes.'
Just one word.
But you women… have to
explain and justify so much.
Sir…
My sons have grown up.
If they accept,
I'd like to get married again.
Good morning, ma'am!
- GOVERMENT-AIDED PRIMARY SCHOOL
- Good morning, Baskar.
- Hello, Baskar. Has Vivek come along?
- Good morning, sir.
He left last night, sir.
I'm on semester leave for a week.
Mom asked me to drop this off.
Arasi, put this in the cupboard, please.
- See you, Ma'am.
- Baskar, just a minute!
Hey, read it out loud!
Nothing urgent.
Just wanted to talk to you.
- Thing is… I, uh…
- Tell me, sir.
Baskar, I…
My friend's a teacher
at a government school in Kallakurichi.
It's been about… two years
since his wife passed.
He's a good man.
Can we…
get Mom married to him?
I already asked her.
She asked me to check with you.
Baskar?
What do you say?
Pass the ball, Bas!
- I'm coming!
- Come, come!
Come on.
Catch! Catch!
Come on, just bowl!
- Catch the ball!
- Come on, bowl!
- I'm off to work. Watch the house.
- Ah, okay.
That evening, when I
was on my way home from work,
my heart was beating so fast.
As a mother, I felt embarassed…
to meet my son.
Do you want tea?
No.
Uh… Baskar…
I left the job at the travel company.
I'm thinking of working in Kerala.
They are paying 15,000 per month.
- And?
- There…
Megala said she’s found
a job as a maid for me.
What's with that look, man?
Don't you want me
to go to Kerala?
The travel company owner
has sent you riyals.
It's in my purse.
I'll give it to you.
Are you… angry with me?
No.
Don't lie to me.
Look at yourself in the mirror.
LOOK AT YOURSELF FIRST!
You're telling me, huh?
Here, look at yourself.
Take a good look.
♪ Your words
They stung me like a scorpion ♪
♪ To whom do I go and cry? ♪
♪ You took away my dreams ♪
♪ Whom do I have now
To lay down my sorrows? ♪
Time's up.
Give that to me, Baskar.
Hey… What is this?
You could've left after the first bell.
If it had been any other exam,
I would’ve left.
♪ Is it right or wrong
I'm wallowing by myself ♪
♪ There are waves of anger
And waves of sorrow ♪
♪ What's this madness?
I don't understand this confusion ♪
♪ Oh, why do you cause me pain
I'm starting to hate you ♪
♪ She taught me life's good and bad ♪
♪ Why is she making these mistakes? ♪
♪ She made a withered leaf
Win against the storm ♪
♪ Why did she have to shatter me? ♪
♪ When the rain stops, umbrella's a pain
I understand that ♪
♪ I'll go as long as life takes me
These tears never stop ♪
SANKARAPURAM, KALLAKURICHI
- [in Malayalam] Who?
- Who was that?
- Selvi!
Selvi?
Close the door.
♪ Dreams, as long as they stay within
Don't cause pain ♪
♪ I suffer so much,
Yet happiness never comes near ♪
♪ No one chooses to be born a woman ♪
♪ She rarely gets the life she wants ♪
♪ I don't understand these laws ♪
♪ Your words and action, they maybe right
My heart can't take it ♪
♪ My heart and soul
They are scarred ♪
♪ These eyes,
They forgot sleep ♪
♪ Your words
They stung me like a scorpion ♪
♪ To whom do I go and cry ♪
♪ You took away my dreams ♪
♪ Whom do I have now
To lay down my sorrows ♪
Brother, this is from your mother.
Do you want the bill?
- Keep the change.
- Okay.
Bro, what currency is this?
Get the money ready.
I'll come get it.
This isn’t a bindi.
It’s a full stop to everything.
Study well.
After that,
I got serious about my studies.
After college, I didn’t want
an engineering job.
So I started an IELTS coaching center.
It’s doing well.
FIVE YEARS LATER
Are you Hari?
- Are you Anu?
- To Ulundurpettai.
- Get in.
- Bro…
Two tickets to Kallakurichi.
We only have sleeper seats.
Will you take it?
Anyone for Karuvathur?
Be careful.
Mind your head.
Hear you go.
[phone ringing]
Sandhya.
- Pick up your phone.
- Just stay silent.
Hello, Mom?
How dare you sleep with him?
- You can't do whatever you want.
- Answer her.
- I sent you to college to study.
- What's his name? Tell me.
Answer me now!
Are you Selvi?
Yes.
My mom is here.
She's furious.
Hang up, Sandhya.
I'll call you later.
To hell with this spinach.
We didn't know
it was a sleeper bus, Selvi.
And just because it was a sleeper bus
doesn’t mean we slept together.
What are you even saying?
- How dare you talk like that--
- Mom, no!
It's not what you think.
We didn't lie down.
We sat with the laptop,
and worked on our project.
That's it.
Stop looking at me like that.
We know our limits, Selvi.
To hell with your limits!
That woman threw your shoes
and is warning me,
that you won't have legs
if you go behind her daughter.
Gosh! Don't get scared over all that.
- What does he expect?
- Selvi…
Gosh!
Do you think I’d follow her
if she didn’t like me?
Huh?
Also,
you taught us not to even look at a girl
if she doesn’t like it.
Selvi, you're a superb mom.
What's her name again?
- Huh?
- Tell me.
Sandhya.
How long have you known her?
Since our first year.
High… since high school.
You better tell me the truth.
She studied in our school
till fifth grade.
- Since then.
- You thief!
Right here?
Since elementary?!
You did all this right under my nose!
God!
What will I even tell your uncle?
That's your problem now?
Go. Tell your favorite son.
Leave me alone.
I'll kill you. Get lost.
- Do whatever you want.
- Marry your son off soon.
I'm definitely leaving this place.
Where will you even go
at this age?
It's not… what you think.
When is Baskar getting married?
Yeah, it's his marriage
I'm thinking about.
Our second-born has brought trouble.
It's not like Baskar will agree
to marry Chittu.
How am I going to get through all this?
Tell me a way.
You keep rotating all the time.
[phone rings]
Baskar!
- Mom?
- Hundred years, darling.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I was just thinking about you.
Did you eat?
What?! Did I eat?
Looks like it's going to rain.
Mom…
Did you cook something,
or is it just black coffee as usual?
I’d have had black coffee if I were alone.
But Vivek’s here.
Yeah, he told me.
Mom…
I… I have something to tell you.
What is it?
Do you need money?
Come on, Mom.
I'm earning now.
Alright. Tell me.
It's…
- I've been talking to my friends.
- About what?
You are alone.
So, I thought…
Why don't you…
get married again?
Okay, hold on.
Mom, your son is calling.
Talk to him and get the marriage fixed,
for him, not me.
- Mom!
- Why are you blabbering like this?
Have you gone mad?
Why are you shouting now?
When you called me,
I thought you had changed.
Now I know.
You've lost your mind.
Mom, just think about it.
Don't make me talk.
Go do your work.
You idiot!
If you're going to bring it up again,
don't call me.
I'll forget that I ever had you.
Mom, it was you
who talked about this to Sir.
I did have an idea then.
Now, I don't.
I'm 42.
Half my head is white.
I've even started dyeing my hair.
You are wasting your time.
And the entire village will spit at me.
So it’s the villagers you’re afraid of.
But you are interested, right?
Don't talk rubbish,
sitting comfortably in Coimbatore.
Come here and try living my life
for a day.
Who will marry you
if I get married at this age?
- I'll take care of my marriage.
- Oh.
- Does Vivek know about this?
- Just say the word.
I'll talk to him.
[phone rings]
So, what does the groom do?
He's in construction.
So, when are you getting married?
Mom, when's the wedding?
I'll kill you.
Selvi, shall we tie the next
banana tree in your house?
This moron keeps yapping
without knowing anything!
Why are you laughing?
You can't play with my life like this.
Do you have a life to play with?
Selvi.
Sandhya's people are torturing her.
They are sending her to college
just for the exams.
So? What are you trying to say?
Selvi, it's…
When are you planning
Baskar's marriage?
Hey, Vivek's in a problem.
He can marry
only after you get married.
Shall I start looking for a girl?
Mom, you can get him married
whenever you want.
But my wedding…
Listen to me carefully.
I’ll get married the same day,
right after you do.
Otherwisw, I'll never get married.
Hey, listen.
Hey, new bride!
How are you?
- I’m good.
- All good on the groom’s side?
- It's alright. Atleast for now.
- Hope it stays that way.
All thanks to you.
Know what matchmaker Moorthy’s
specialty is?
I don’t just seal the deal.
I stick around for
the after service, too.
- How are you?
- Hello, Selvi.
I'll hang up.
So, what’s the occasion?
You know why we've come to see you.
Here.
Lord Muruga!
If I find a girl for Baskar,
won’t your brother come after me?
I’ll see to it.
Not just you,
everyone will see me get ripped apart.
Alright.
Tell me.
- Should she be working, or--
- That’s not a concern.
The moment he sees her,
he should want to marry her.
- Get me a girl like that.
- Consider it done!
So we’ll get this done soon, yeah?
Madam, you just shared his picture.
You can’t rush this
like sealing a water can.
- We're talking about marriage!
- Okay, take care of it.
But send him the photos today, okay?
Huh? And?
Really, Mom?
Yes.
I’ll get married.
But first, you’ll get some photos
from the matchmaker.
Go through the girls’ photos.
If any of them catch your eye,
talk to her parents.
Tell them about our deal.
Alright?
- What "our deal", Mom?
- What else?
Tell them that, "I need to settle
my mom’s marriage first.
Only after that can we marry."
Alright? If they're okay with that,
you can start finding me a match.
You promise?
Yes, I promise.
Thanks, Mom!
No dad’s going to agree to this!
If Baskar ends up liking her,
he won’t bother me anymore, right?
They talk big about
their mom’s marriage
until a pretty girl
catches their eye!
Come in!
Excuse me?
Hello?
Action!
Surprise!
Hey, darlings.
Welcome to the Kimki Channel.
This is Baskar.
You haven’t met
Baskar before, right?
Guess what?
We’re meeting Baskar
for the first time, too!
Where are you running off to?
In this video...
Get in here!
You’ll get to know
who Baskar is and why he’s here.
Cut!
I'm Vandhana's mom
and he's her dad, Kimki.
Hi! Welcome.
Baskar, he’s the biggest fan
of Korean director Kim Ki-duk!
Come.
Make way for the groom!
Hey, darlings!
Meet Baskar. Groom No. 1,
Vandhana’s first match.
- Baskar, don’t hide your face.
- Say hi to the viewers.
- Please stop doing this.
- Baskar!
You’ve got lakhs watching you!
Give us a smile.
Sir!
Did you mention she’s a YouTuber
in the matrimony profile?
I can't talk here.
Let me see the girl.
I’ll be on my way.
Viewers, he’s really excited
to see his bride!
He’ll tell us how it went
once he’s back.
Vandhana's upstairs.
Go on.
Really?
Okay, got it.
Okay, Mom.
I'll take care.
Hi.
I'm Vandhana.
Baskar.
Baskar, your profile was interesting.
A mechatronics degree,
and now IELTS coaching?
How come?
For my own professional satisfaction.
I…
Listen.
I hate arranged marriages.
Feels like browsing and picking.
Then why are you here?
That is...
I had to rethink things
because of my mom.
Why?
I can’t explain that now.
Sorry for taking up your time.
I better get going.
I'm sorry.
Hello!
You come all the way here, say you hate
arranged marriages, and just leave?
It's my fault.
Forgive me.
I can’t stand all that shooting
setup down there!
I should go.
Excuse me!
Baskar.
You gave them roughly 90 seconds
of footage when you arrived, right?
Before you even start your bike,
I’ll have everything uploaded!
Mind it!
Any idea how many subscribers
we’ve got?
1.8 million.
Even a 60-second clip of them talking
can bring in big viewership.
What are you going to do?
So, when your mother
wanted to remarry,
you were against it?
Yes.
So what led to your enlightenment?
I brought my mother over to Coimbatore
since she was all by herself
after I started my coaching center.
I turned my old office into my home.
Whenever I checked the CCTV,
trapped inside four walls,
she kept doing chores,
with no one to talk to.
It really started weighing on me.
Look, a rat’s trapped!
Look!
The way she stood there…
she looked like a caged rat
holding another rat in a trap.
Guilt crept in,
like I’d ruined my mom’s life.
I went to meet Sister Angela.
So, now you feel guilty
about your mother, right?
Baskar, let me answer
as a biology student.
Every living human,
or rather, any living being,
has primary needs.
Basic needs.
Know what that is?
Eating.
Sleeping.
And the third is…
Finding a partner.
Right?
Without the first two,
we can’t survive.
And the third?
Physical needs.
Sure, we can live without it.
But it’ll eat us up inside.
That’s exactly why marriage exists.
Sister, may I be frank?
My mom is already 42.
Do you think
she still wants to get married?
It is optional, Baskar.
We’re nuns.
We’ve chosen celibacy.
We have a divine calling.
So we chose this path.
But if your mother wants to marry,
that’s her call to make.
Hey, stop rubbing your eye.
Close your eyes for a minute.
And…
Instead of just looking at someone
and wondering if he’s hungry,
humanity is asking him
if he wants to eat.
She's your mom.
Try asking her that.
Baskar?
Now, open your eyes.
That day,
Sister truly opened my eyes.
Wow.
Superb.
Amazing!
Only then did I start talking
to my mom about marriage.
Good job.
Baskar, you know what?
Even I hate this whole
browsing-and-picking
arranged-marriage setup.
Then why all this?
My dad came up with this
to increase the subscriber count.
He turned my matchmaking
into content.
Alright.
I need to find a girl to show my mom
and get her okay to remarry.
And you’re looking for
matchmaking content.
Then let’s make a deal
without telling our families.
A fake drama.
I don't get it.
Action!
Hi, Kimkis!
Baskar and I really clicked.
Not just me,
even my mom and dad love Baskar!
Comment below and tell us
what you think about us.
She's indeed beautiful.
But are they truly okay
with me remarrying?
Mom, you promised!
Don’t back out now.
Get dolled up
and wait inside.
Manohar will be there tomorrow
to take your photos.
For the matrimonial profile.
I'll hang up.
COIMBATORE
Hey, what’s with the sudden visit?
Vivek. Hey!
Get up.
Have this.
What's wrong, man?
Vivek, what was that for?
What's up with you?
Why are you bothering Mom?
Oh, so this is how
she’s doing things now?
Of course she’ll come to me.
What about it?
Is she uncomfortable with marriage,
or is it getting in your way?
Yes, it’s affecting my marriage.
Did mother pressure you
to get her remarried?
Did she? Did she?
Tell me!
She did.
At the age of 35!
How dare you?
How can you even imagine
another man in his place?
Won’t you ever think about Mom?
Mom is still alive.
She’s not interested
in marriage at this age.
Drop it.
I’ll take care of her like a queen.
As if!
We only go home twice.
Even then, we’re glued to our phone
or talking to someone else.
Do we ever sit
and talk to Mom properly?
This guy, I swear!
You pass your broken phone to Mom,
and you claim you’ll
treat her like a queen?
Do we even know her number?
Look!
She has a life of her own.
It’s not for us to decide.
This is pure exploitation, man!
In the name of mother's love…
Do you expect every son
to ask his widowed mother
if she wants to remarry?
- Tell me!
- Yes!
They should!
They should, man!
They should.
Like our mom,
who was widowed at 25.
Even at the age of 40 or 50,
her son, daughters,
heck even her father
should ask her if she wants to remarry.
Listen.
Feels like I’m looking at myself
from four years ago.
It'll take another four years
for you to realize all this.
By the time we’ll get old…
God, I can’t wait that long.
You leave.
Won't you just drop it?
- Won't you?
- I won't, damn it!
Let me go!
I'll just--
[phone rings]
Write it.
In big letters.
- Go on.
- Big enough to scream shame.
It's time she knew our power.
- Who’s writing on my walls?
- Here she is!
- Smack him.
- Back off!
- Hey, Selvi!
- Pachaperumal!
Why are you just standing there?
Who is he?
He’s the financier
who gave you the money.
Listen!
After all the debts
your husband left behind,
you came to my finance company,
saying you didn’t even have
money for your kids’ studies
and held my partner’s feet and begged!
You’ve forgotten, huh?
Selling this house won’t even
cover the interest.
How long has it been, huh?
You send reminder letters, don’t you?
You’re supposed to put up a notice.
Instead, you’re scribbling on walls?
If you delay payment,
not just on the walls,
they’ll write on you, too.
I heard you went to a financier
for your kids’ studies?
Why worry?
I'm here for you.
Hey!
Look--
I won't go easy on you!
You deface my walls,
and you dare raise your voice?
Have you lost your senses?
Pachaperumal is all red now!
Why haven't you done
anything about this?
- You could've painted over it.
- Come in, brother?
Welcome, Uncle.
We've paid them back, Uncle.
They said they'll send their men.
Let them remove it.
I just stopped by at Pachaperumal's
to yell at him.
He's rambling about calling
for a meeting, it seems.
Like he would.
He’s still a snake,
waiting to strike again.
Vivek, serve Uncle his coffee.
What happened at Coimbatore?
Did you talk?
What did he say?
I'll tell you.
Want me to loan some of
Aunty's jewels for cash?
- No need, Uncle.
- Here you go, Uncle.
- Careful. It's hot.
- Selvi,
Chittu's growing old
and you haven't said anything yet.
Do you expect me
to fall at your feet?
Tell me when
we'll get them married!
Why don't you ask him yourself?
Why the hurry to get her married?
She's still in school.
Plus, there’s a six-year gap
between us.
You know the legal minimum age
for a girl to marry is 18.
Like the folks at our village follow that!
None of your law matters here.
Law, it seems.
There's also a law which allows
widow to remarry.
Does that mean we can get
your mother married again?
Careful, dear.
Help her out, boys.
I'll go.
Hey, you keep Uncle company.
- Wha--
- Vivek?
Come, sit.
He threw me under the bus.
He's a studious idiot.
Ran to the law to escape me.
You tell me, Vivek.
Uncle?
What do you say?
What do I say…
Do you think I'm a fool over here?!
- Selvi? Selvi!
- Huh?
What… What happened?
- I won't put up with this, Selvi.
- Wha…
One of them will be my son-in-law.
- I won't step in until you agree!
- But…
Don't you dare take me for a fool!
- I will end you all!
- Brother…
Please wait!
Let's talk this out!
What did he say?
- Forget about Un--
- You…
Can't believe you're my children!
All my fate!
[phone rings]
Hey, what's happening?
- I'll talk to you later.
- Wait, wait!
Why didn't you call me after
going to Coimbatore.
What happened?
Did you even go?
I did go, but…
Go on, tell me!
- I said I'll talk to you later.
- Vivek…
Vivek, I’m in a tight spot right now!
Tell me what went down there!
Sandhya, I tried my best,
but he's hell-bent on getting her married.
We got into an argument
and even fought a bit.
And then?
His stance and his explanation
slowly made sense to me.
So?
So…
Mom needs to live her life, too.
Why did you two fight?
I mean, I didn't have the strength
to accept it, at first.
Then I decided…
…to side with him.
Hello?
You there, Sandhya?
Vivek…
I'm trying so hard to convince
my parents about us!
I don't even think you realise that.
They're already drilling me
about our caste and status differences,
- and this nonsense to top it all?!
- Sandhya!
Don't dismiss it as nonsense.
My mother's wedding
is equally important.
Vivek…
I wasn't dismissing
or opposing her remarriage.
Which girl's dad will accept
for such conditions?
- Why won't we sort ours--
- Listen to me.
My mother hasn't accepted yet.
It's a long process…
Don't ask me about it
and piss me off!
Sandhya, I don't have an answer
to your hows and whys.
If convincing your parents is our issue,
so is my mother's remarriage.
We've got to figure this out together.
Sandhya? Are you there?
Say something!
Sandhya?
I'm talking to you!
You…
You let me go, Vivek.
I don't think this will work out.
- What?
- I'll get back to studying.
Let's take a break.
You keep escaping by wanting
a break every time we fight!
I wasn't--
I wasn't trying to escape.
- Don't raise your voice at me.
- I wasn't. But make it clear.
Do you want a break from me
or break up with me?
Tell me.
Answer me!
What do you want?!
Do I have to say it?
Let's break up!
Fine, let's break up!
Dang it!
Out of my way.
- This is all your fault.
- What?!
You started it, though!
You asked Sir to ask me, didn't you?
I asked… but when are you replying?
My remarriage would ruin
both your lives.
It won't. We'll be alright.
Oh, really?
Didn't you see him cry?
What was it?
Break up, huh?
Your lives will break up, as well!
- Mom, they'll be al--
- You.
I am not agreeing
even if you two team up!
I won't…
…remarry at this age!
And who do you think you are
to decide my life for me?
[phone rings]
Pick up.
Must be from your girl.
Hi, how are you?
Why didn't you tell us
you were going home?
Had you told us,
I would've sent in a hidden camera.
You could've recorded
your trip for us to use.
It's rare to see a mother and son
having a heart-to-heart, you know?
Also, I heard something.
I felt bad when I found out
you fought with your brother.
That would've been
such amazing content!
Usually, these family vloggers stick to
safe stuff like singing and dancing.
None of them have fought!
Had you recorded it all,
we'd be handed a silver button
for its virality!
- Why don't you--
- You idiot!
Why do you turn everything
into content? It's sickening!
This is our life!
Our personal space!
Do you think it's a content for you?
If you want a silver button,
beg in the streets, record it,
and upload it.
Give the phone to Vandana!
Baskar's on the line.
- Hi!
- Vandana, I'm sorry.
I don't think this will work out.
What won't work out?
My mom isn't…
Hang on, I'll give it to her.
Tell her, Mom.
This is the girl from that channel.
Tell her you're not remarrying
at any cost.
Go on, tell her!
Tell her, just like you told me.
Saw that?
I won’t be getting married either.
We don't have to
put up an act anymore.
We can end our agreement
and the fake drama!
Okay?
I'm sorry.
Bye.
- What’s going on?
- Come on, tell us.
Aren't you two running late?
Come on. Eat your dinner.
Where is he going?
Ask him to eat, first.
- Vivek?
- Mom!
You said we were important.
When we agreed to see you remarry,
- why are you being a coward?
- We'll talk about this later.
Eat up before you leave.
- Vivek?
- You eat it all.
Bas? Bas, wait!
Where will you two eat at this hour?
Don't leave with an empty stomach!
Baskar!
I didn't expect my children
would agree to my remarriage.
I wanted to divert
their attention from this
and decided to scare them…
Yes, sir. I'll work for you.
…by leaving my phone at home
and going to Kerala.
To those who might find out
where I was headed,
We're on a pilgrimage walk
to Maruvathur.
When I saw Mother Mary's procession,
I changed my mind.
But then…
[phone rings]
Brother Baskar?
Shoo!
Go away, you!
Can you check her recent calls?
Last called is a number
saved 'Kerala Sir'.
What, 'Kerala Sir?'
They told me
she was at Melmaruvathur.
Check if she's there!
This is yours, Vivek.
- How's school, Chittu?
- It's going alright.
Mom, hurry!
I'm running late for school!
- I'm coming!
- Bas…
Your mother remembered
to wear my saree to the temple.
But she couldn't inform us
before leaving, huh?
Had she did,
I could've given her my safebox.
All at home have no idea
about her missing
thinking she's gone
to Melmaruvathur.
And you two want
to complain to the police?!
It would be a shame if this got out.
If your mother
intentionally left her phone behind
and went out
without telling either of you,
it suggests
she disapproves
of what you’re up to.
Not again…
It’s probably something
you’re not listening to her about.
I'm certain she wants Chittu
as her daughter-in-law!
Of course, I know my sister!
[phone rings]
What I'm trying to say is…
Hello?
Yes, Motcham Rani.
You've been with the patient
for three days.
Ma'am.
Where did you see her?
I didn't see her, but heard her.
- You heard her?
- Yes, ma'am.
We were on our way to
Malai Madha Church in a procession
crossing Kallerikuppam when…
- Lord Ayyanar, save me!
- Oh, no…
- What's wrong?
- I heard a loud cry.
- Is it?
- Hurry, hurry!
- I can't see anyone, Motcham.
- It sounded like a woman!
I clearly heard them screaming,
"Lord Ayyanar, save me!"
Don't just stare at the well, Motcham.
Why would a lady be out
at this hour?
Don't be stubborn about it.
Let's get back, people!
To hell with her scream…
Let's be on our way, Motcham.
- Motcham, don't.
- Hey, what are you doing?!
Hey, come on.
You don't have to.
Don't cry, dear boy.
- Please don't cry.
- Doctor, come with me please.
Motcham, come with me.
You too, boys.
Come with me.
When will we get her final report?
As soon as the MRI results are in.
All of you must sign.
Even you, boys.
Sure, ma'am.
They've come out.
You can go in, boys.
She says a hog butt her into the well.
I asked her why she left without
telling us.
But she never said a word.
She kept mum about it.
What really happened, Bas?
Do you know anything?
Tell us if you do.
Okay, that's enough.
She was in a coma for a day, right?
It must be hard
to remember things at once.
Baskar, take him with you
and visit your mother.
Wa-- Wait a minute
I've got something to tell her.
See how he runs to her
before her own kids.
My children…
Don't strain yourself to talk.
I'll figure it out.
I understand how you must feel
with Vivek and Baskar
unwilling to step forward
to marry Chittu.
But you jumping into the well
was stupid!
I mean, it did work out
because your boys
are scared to bits!
I'll send them in now.
Brainwash either of them
to be my son-in-law, okay?
I'll see you.
Ugh…
The moment I hit my head,
all I could think was…
will I ever see my children again?
I shouldn't have…
put my babies through so much.
Sorry, Mom.
Forgive me, Mom.
I should've apologised.
But didn't.
Because if I did,
they'd bring up my remarriage.
So, I remained quiet.
You wrapped everything up, yeah?
Not like I had a choice.
Her life's more important
than her remarriage.
Have they discharged her?
Yeah. Vivek's with her.
- Coffee?
- Black.
Hey.
Hey, Baskar?!
What's wrong?
Baskar?
What happened?!
Baskar!
What's wrong?
Why're you crying?
Mom…
Mom will be all alone
drinking black coffee by herself.
♪ From far clouds comes a gentle tear
Which root it finds is never clear ♪
♪ No one’s seen it anywhere here ♪
♪ Wind hits bamboo all along
When does it change into a song? ♪
♪ No one’s known it all this long ♪
♪ My heart’s restless, it slips away ♪
♪ It runs to you, won’t ever stay ♪
♪ I tried, I held ♪
♪ But I fell through ♪
♪ Dreams are falling like a stream
Filling up my eyes with gleam ♪
♪ I beckoned you with my touch ♪
You like him?!
You wretch.
We let you be for a night
and this is what you do to the house?!
- You vermin!
- Of course, I'd do this!
- As if Dad's actions were justifiable.
- So?
- You want to accept your nonsense?
- Punish me then!
Instead, you vandalized their walls.
How is it fair?
He never once spoke ill of you!
So this was your revenge?
- Sir?
- Check who's by the door.
Senthil sir?
God, ugh! I paid for
all those art classes for this?!
- I curse you!
- Stop hitting me!
I asked you to bring people over
to scrub that off.
They're here and on it, already!
Paint over that crap, man.
Make it quick
before someone knows.
- Driver?
- Yeah.
I wonder how she climbed up
those high walls and painted this!
It's confusing!
That's love.
You'll never know.
- Me?
- Yeah.
♪ Touch me slow,
I was bare ground ♪
FEW MONTHS LATER
Here, man.
Fetch me some water, buddy.
Here, Shankar.
Hurry, hurry!
Drink a little, dear.
This moron…
Here you go.
Dang it, he's smart.
No!
My precious boy's here!
My poor baby!
Dear!
Don't scream loudly, dear.
She's going into labor, oh God!
- Water! Someone fetch some water!
- Move! Move!
Careful, Selvi!
Two lives are at risk!
Baskar!
Baskar, bring the stretcher over.
- Get here quick!
- Lift up! Lift up!
Move! Move!
Move, please!
Lay her down
on the stretcher.
Be careful of her legs.
Oh, God!
Dear!
- My dear!
- Baskar?
Don't stall and take her quickly!
Be quick! She's in grave danger!
Follow us on your bike, Baskar.
Go! Go! All will be fine!
Hey, come on! Get the bike!
Selvi, come eat.
It's getting late.
Let's go.
Let me rush to the bathroom quick.
Great timing.
Hurry up and don't delay!
Now why are you
putting on an act by crying?
You've been crying like you know them!
Who do you think you are?
Sivaji or Savithri?!
How dare you call me that?
I'm putting on a show, huh?!
Well, tell me!
Am I a drama queen?
I knew Megala as a child
who now has a child of her own!
I was 26
when I lost my husband.
But she? She's barely 20.
From now on, she won’t feel safe
around anyone in this village.
Her life's already over
even before it could begin!
The end.
Damn this life!
You know what this feels like, right?
Can’t you try to change it?
Start small at least
to create a ripple of change!
Of course, it'll be difficult
with many opposing
and causing trouble.
But the tears that come
once you get past it, is the real deal.
And what you did now,
is just an act.
If you want Megala's life
and the lives of women seperated
from their husbands to get better,
- you make the first move.
- Baskar, that’s enough.
Move.
Only when you remarry at 43,
will our 23 year old Megala
and other Megalas will get a better life!
Until then, your crying
and whining is all a show!
You're Sivaji and Savithri!
I'm done with you.
Selvi?
Are you coming or not?
♪ A woman's heart is an endless sea ♪
[phone ringing]
♪ No shore can hold its mystery ♪
Driver, can you turn
the volume down a bit?
Mom?
Mom!
Go ahead.
Mom…
Proceed with it.
We'll face, come what may.
We'll go ahead, Mom.
We'll proceed.
We'll proceed!
Let's go ahead!
♪ Hey yo, hey yo
Where’s your guy, yo? ♪
♪ Who is he? Who could it be?
Who’s your man, tell me! ♪
♪ Hey yo, hey yo,
Wedding bells say hey yo! ♪
We'll deal with this privately
till my Mom finds a partner.
♪ Hey yo, hey yo
Leaves and trees all say so! ♪
You might have to move with me
to Kuwait after the wedding.
Find someone who lives
within overnight reach of me.
To hell with Kuwait, Muscat…
♪ Who is he? Who could it be?
Where is he? ♪
♪ One by one, it’s falling in
Run and chase it, let’s begin ♪
So what if he's a priest?
No, no.
We read that you're a priest.
- At which temple?
- Yep, I am a priest.
My temple…
Look over there!
Sairam! Sairam!
♪ Family lines up, gifts to give
Gold in hand; let’s start to live! ♪
♪ Tie his heart and make him stay
First night shows the way ♪
♪ Still a world you’ve yet to see
In the dark, just you and he ♪
♪ Hey yo, hey yo
Where’s your guy, yo? ♪
♪ Who is he? Who could it be?
Who’s your man, tell me! ♪
♪ Hundreds of joys, sweet as can be
Honey-like love flowing free ♪
♪ Love and desire, both in play
Who can keep them both away? ♪
♪ Hey yo, hey yo,
Wedding bells say hey yo! ♪
♪ Even if sleep drifts far away
It still feels like a concert play ♪
♪ Hey yo, hey yo
Where’s your guy, yo? ♪
♪ The dream I kept within my sight
He’ll give it to me-- ♪
How many tickets did that lady buy?
Did she offer to buy for the broker?
First, buy your ticket!
Tickets, tickets…
To where, ma'am?
Got spare change?
FEW MONTHS LATER
Mother Mary, their pilgrimage was ruined
last year because of my accident.
I humbly pray that
you grant Motcham’s wish.
Mother Mary, let my wish
be fulfilled this year.
Please help us find
a bride for Ezhumalai!
Getting hungry?
- Hang on, I'll untie you--
- Motcham?
Hey, come on in!
- Dear?
- Every morning you pester me!
Selvi's here.
- Welcome. Come on in.
- Where's Brother?
Must be out fetching water.
Wait, I'll call him here.
Someone said they'll come
in the afternoon.
What made you come early?
Motcham, both of you
come to Ezhumalai's house.
Come, let's be on our way.
- I thought I'd spend some time in--
- As if!
Like that's the reason
you got here early.
I'll be back
to take you grazing, okay?
I’m taking my girl
to meet her man.
I know you told your cow
I'm your girl.
But I'll decide if he's my man!
Take your sweet time.
No one's rushing.
- We're here.
- Hi, Motcham!
Is she a guest?
What's the occasion?
I mean, it is an occasion.
- I'll tell you later.
- Alright, be well.
- Granny?
- Who's asking?
Come in!
- Granny?
- Yeah?
Don't just stand here. Come close!
Don't be afraid.
I saved you from the deepest well,
but he's just got a pumpset.
Come on in.
Hello, Granny.
- Oh, is this Motcham?
- Yes, yes.
- Who's with you?
- She's um…
- I'll tell you.
- Okay.
Hey, go look around.
- Off you go.
- Go, dear.
Granny, she is Ezhumalai's…
Welcome! Welcome!
Thought I'd fetch some water
before bringing the curry to a boil.
Arokia just told me
about your visit.
Gosh, the sun's really blistering!
I wonder how you walked in this heat.
I couldn't--
Careful!
You might burn yourself.
Go on.
You can try it out.
Please.
Don't expect it to be great.
Also, don’t be surprised to see
so many kitchen appliances here.
I bought this for my wife
when she was alive.
I know pretty accessories
make them happy.
But I felt the best thing I could do
was buy her kitchen appliances
to make her life easier.
Ezhumalai, I'm leaving.
Got to take the cows grazing.
Brother, can you drop Selvi
by the riverside?
- She'll go from there.
- Alright.
- Bye, Selvi!
- No, I--
Hey, I can drop you off.
Don't worry. Give me a minute.
I was 19 when I went to Oman.
I was farming there, too.
Date palms!
Twenty years went just like that
in a desert.
You know,
Oman's an Arab country.
I know.
Muscat is its airport, right?
My, my!
How do you know that?
I was working in a travel agency.
Riyal is it's currency, right?
I have a keepsake of it.
Ah, I too have one!
Come over here.
See this?
Take a closer look!
Recognise the 'sheikh?'
Yep, that's me!
It's alright, you can laugh at it!
Why…
Why have you stuck that there?
I owe my life to Oman.
Despite its barren dunes,
you must remain grateful.
Come along.
I think I went home only four times.
Ah, popsicles!
Sir…
Two, please.
- I… don't want.
- Have a bite!
- It's… alright.
- Ah, eat one to beat the heat.
- No, I really don't want.
- Oh, yeah?
Alright then.
Only after, Sembaruthi, my daughter
got married did she realise
that I also remarry,
so I won't be alone.
How sloppy can I be!
You're laughing for this, too?
Do you want me to be happy
that I'm with you
or sad because
I let my icecream melt?
It's only ice. It melts even if it falls
on sand or in my mouth.
It's taking its course.
And we'll take ours!
What do you mean by ours?
Ours is… staying happy!
Looking on the bright side feels nice.
But keeping that hope alive is tough.
Why not?
You have me, now.
All this anger and sorrow in us
must remain in us.
We mustn't be slaves to it.
You must know that
happy people aren't fools.
Your friend, Motcham,
asked me to drop you by the river.
And I took my bike out.
But did I actually drop you?
Does that make me a fool?
Fine, tell me why you're happy?
Because I really, really like you!
Why?
Ask this when someone
doesn't like you.
How are you so clueless?
Let me… take the bike from here on.
You can walk along.
Why do you seem quiet?
No, I…
I'm not able to be happy like you.
Eh? Why not?
Not sure what my kids think…
You can think about that afterwards.
Let's start with
you doing the things you like.
And when they start liking me,
you can be even happier!
See, we must never waste a day.
We're in our 40s!
In our 20s, a day might count as a day.
As we grow into our 40s,
a day feels like a year!
Also,
I remembered something
when you mentioned about your kids.
The person you met at home,
is my aunt.
She is paralyzed.
So, she eats, sleeps,
goes to the loo…
…all on the bed.
She'll remain my responsibility
even after our wedding.
She's not your responsibilty.
Make sure your sons know about this.
Hey…
You're walking away
without a word?
If I’m to be anything,
I want to be like you.
All I feel is
the need to be with you.
♪ Talking with you, I began to fly
Carried in a dreamy sky ♪
♪ Walking ahead, I slowly fell
Like a tender rain that softly fell ♪
♪ My heart runs wild
With endless waves ♪
♪ A gentle rain that softly stays ♪
♪ I melt away in love’s own blaze ♪
♪ I wandered long to find my own ♪
♪ Days kept fading, I was alone ♪
♪ And today, I found you ♪
♪ No one was mine till this day ♪
♪ Now it’s us, come what may ♪
♪ A net of memories drifting free ♪
♪ Eyes that speak but lose to me ♪
I like him.
Baskar and Vivek will like him, right?
Tell me!
Tell me that they will.
Like you can answer me any way.
♪ A dream that feels unreal ♪
♪ Or a memory I can’t hold still?
I’m lost and still ♪
- I like him.
- ♪ A moon that draws so close to me ♪
♪ Something only my heart knows?
I’m lost in its flow ♪
♪ Thinking of you! ♪
- Do you have a picture of her?
- No, dear.
You really don't?
Dad?
Got it from Motcham Sister.
Alright, dear.
♪ Is this a love that never fades? ♪
♪ What is this tie we’ve drawn upon? ♪
♪ A bond that time has carried on ♪
♪ Is this a search that never ends? ♪
♪ My heart crosses every distance ♪
♪ Pleading with quiet pain ♪
♪ Feels like a dream
I can’t quite see ♪
♪ Still my hands reach out
To you and me ♪
♪ You’re you, I’m me, worlds apart ♪
♪ Yet many roads can meet our hearts ♪
♪ So many longings fill me inside ♪
♪ Searching for you
We slowly collide ♪
♪ In the silence of words we hide
Desire comes rushing inside ♪
♪ The time will come
We’ll fall into place ♪
♪ The moment will run
For our hands to embrace ♪
♪ All our doubts will slip away ♪
♪ Every barrier will change one day ♪
♪ A dream that feels unreal ♪
♪ Or a memory I can’t hold still?
I’m lost and still ♪
♪ A moon that draws so close to me ♪
♪ Something only my heart knows?
I’m lost in its flow ♪
♪ Thinking of you! ♪
♪ A dream that feels unreal ♪
Which one of them is the--
Ezhumalai?
- This is her son.
- Hello.
I swear, Ezhumalai.
- Don't bother about him.
- Baskar?
Since today's an auspicious day,
we thought we'd fix their wedding date.
Give that to me.
Whoa. Hold up.
Hang on a minute.
Why don't we take this slow?
- Because…
- What's wrong?
Since this is the first time here,
we'll visit your place, tomorrow.
Also, we need Vivek's approval.
Let's see…
if everything falls in place.
When it does, we'll fix the date
on an auspicious day!
Alright, dear. Alright.
Mom, I'm stopping by
at Manohar's place.
Sleep this way, dear,
and stretch out your feet.
You heard what the doctor said, right?
Perumayi?
What happened?
Why are you here
without sending them to school?
What a sudden surprise, Perumayi!
What brings you here?
- You'll have some koozh?
- Garnish it with some poison for me.
I'd rather die than stay alive!
What's wrong with her?
What happened, dear?
Mom will tell you, Granny.
Where's Brother?
- Hello, Baskar!
- Hi!
You two keep talking.
We'll join you in a while.
Okay.
She took such good care of us,
wouldn't she know
what's best for her own life?
Which is why,
whatever Mom likes,
we’ll support it too!
I scared you good, huh?
Nah, nah.
Must've been the others.
I knew you'd have your reasons
since you're a well educated boy.
Um…
Can I…
Can I know what that was?
Before I got here,
I first visited my Aunt.
Baskar, here you go.
- What's the matter?
- You know how…
Mom… for a long time…
She's been alone for a long time.
So… I thought…
Get up, you scoundrel!
And get out of my house!
Do the same for your aunt
and her children! I dare you!
Now every relative will line up
to try and shatter Mom's strength.
Another thing.
Since I didn't want everyone to know
when the wedding is,
I couldn't give my approval
in the morning.
Sorry.
So…
We're getting married in secret?
That… is impossible
because my aunt
must've told her parents by now.
And it won't take long
for the news to spread from there.
The only information they'll receive
is of your marriage.
But when it is happening
is something they'll never, ever know.
Make sure of it, okay?
Can I know when I'm getting married?
When's the wedding?
Tell me.
See that?
It's when the sun sets
and rises again.
You mean, in the morning?
Tomorrow?!
This is a wedding!
- We've to get the thaali, decor--
- We must make haste.
I haven't conveyed this
to my mom yet.
I just decided this.
I'll take care of it all.
I'll let you know
in which temple it will be in.
- See you! He'll convey everything!
- [both] Sure, dear. See you!
Dad?
Yes, dear.
You can call those
near and dear to you.
I noticed I made my sister
upset in the morning.
So, I'd like to…
Sembaruthi's her name, right?
Yeah.
I'll invite Sembaruthi myself.
Baskar?
You’ve been my saving grace.
Actually…
Mom just met you
and I just met you.
We have no idea who you are
and trust you blindly
to marry our mother.
I ask you…
to please be
my mother's saving grace!
Alright, dear!
Alright!
Of course!
Lord Muruga!
- What’s happening here?
- How would I know?
- Priest…
- Muruga!
He never comes to the temple.
Why's he here today?
He handed me 500 rupees
and asked for a marriage setup.
He’s not saying anything about
the bride or groom.
He hasn’t mentioned
the muhurtham time either.
He’ll come just
ten minutes before
and wants the temple to be opened.
Who is getting married here?
Who told you this, Dad?
Let’s discuss it.
Excuse me!
Did Vivek’s brother tell you
that we're getting married?
Why isn’t he revealing
the bride and groom?
Go ask him.
Maybe his friends are getting married.
Why can’t it be Bhaskar?
What is this nonsense?
Dad, I have a lot to study.
I’m going to my room.
If you don’t trust me,
lock me from outside.
- Vivek, are you at the hostel?
- What’s going on?
Why pension till death?
Shouldn't I remarry?
We did search for a groom
for Selvi’s remarriage.
But I don’t know who this groom is.
Hold this, it’s ringing.
- Who is this?
- Bhaskar…
Are you arranging your
mother’s wedding in our temple?
It's Pachaperumal here.
Look, you come from a family
that lived well.
I’m struggling for a life
that shouldn’t be wasted.
I dare you to stop the wedding.
Her own sons are arranging her wedding.
Why should we interfere?
We must stop it.
It'll make sense to interfere,
had it been an inter-caste marriage.
Hey!
We protect caste
only through women.
Only by controlling them
can we keep caste order intact.
Selvi.
Please come in, brother.
- Dear…
- What happened to your phone?
Sit down.
Have you made tea?
Hey idiot, did you come here
just to drink tea?
Hey, sit down!
Tell me, who among you has
truly kept your wife happy?
How can they be happy
after marrying us?
Even after we hit them for small things,
they stay for the kids
and endure everything.
- Correct!
- But, now…
if Selvi, without a husband,
gets married at 43,
will the women here stay quiet?
They’ll get the courage to
leave their abusive husbands
- and marry the right man.
- Makes sense.
Will caste even matter
to them by then?
Forget what her sons say.
Doesn't she have sense?
She’s going to ruin the town’s respect.
I have three daughters.
If they know I’m your sister,
no one will marry my daughters.
My sister-in-laws
already don’t respect me.
If you do this shameful thing,
I’ll be crying all my life.
Why were you even born to me?
We were living in peace.
Go die somewhere.
If Selvi gets married,
the next generation will also
forget our caste pride,
and will walk the same path
wishing their mothers to be happy.
Aristotle, if I see you talking to Baskar,
I'll kick you out.
We don’t need to be that smart.
She calls herself a mother?
You should’ve done this
when your sons were young.
Why do this rubbish now?
Is this necessary at this age?
She’s still not satisfied.
I came to your house with my kids
and begged you to stay with me.
Did you come?
You didn’t!
You're 66 and you still want
to be with your husband.
Why? Are you not satisfied?
Okay, leave it.
You shouldn't have said that.
You, too.
It's her life.
It should be her choice.
Selvi, go.
Make tea for everyone.
Get up.
Just go.
Just finish her off.
This is what she deserves.
- Close the door.
- Move!
Marriage?
My foot!
Don't let go!
We're supposed to pay the price
for your decisions?
Don't let go!
Brother, please spare her!
How dare you
talk to your mother like that?
Kill her!
- Finish her!
- Brother, please let go!
Mom, please!
Tell him to back off!
You’ll get married
and leave me ruined?
Don't spare her!
You witch!
What the hell, Mom!
Leave her.
Choke her to death!
Go on!
- Mom, please listen to me.
- You swine, rot in hell!
- Hey, back off!
- Mom, please!
Shut up.
She deserves it!
Brother, she'll die, please.
Please, brother!
She’ll go away,
just let her go!
Brother, come.
We have to know
who's marrying Selvi.
But before that,
we need to know the date.
Sister Selvi…
She's dead.
Go check.
Oh God!
Sister! Sister!
What happened, sister?
Sister!
Wake up, sister!
Careful, sister.
Slowly.
What did they do to you?
Drink some.
Drink.
Easy, sister.
Thank God…
you came.
Sister…
I’m taking the baby and catching
the first bus tomorrow to his town.
Sister, don't take me wrong.
The rumour is…
Sister…
People like us…
once we become mothers,
we’re meant to stay
this way forever, aren’t we?
If we wish to remarry…
what’s the point, sister?
If Megala’s life has to move forward,
if women separated
from their husbands deserve change,
you take the first step.
See you, Sister.
Be brave.
Take care.
There, there.
Alright, sweetie.
We have to stop this.
Let's smash her house down!
We’d rather lose a life
than let this wedding happen!
What day it is?
Only one person has bought
a nuptial thread from us.
Even I thought
people don’t usually buy
nuptial threads on Tuesdays.
That's right.
Where is he from?
What is it, Grandma?
Hey!
She’s ninety years old!
She’s lived alone for years now!
You’re getting your
mother remarried, right?
Might as well get her married too.
Someone has to light her pyre.
Hey! Let go!
Hey!
Catch him! Go! Go!
Fast!
Come fast!
He's going this way!
Come!
Stop right there!
You're a disgrace to this town!
[phone rings]
Yes, Megala.
- Baskar, I went to your house.
- Yes, tell me.
Brother?
Hello?
Manohar, get here as soon as possible.
Sir, some men beat me up
so the wedding wouldn’t happen.
Look!
They tore my shirt off, sir.
This is my friend’s brother’s shirt.
Okay. And?
What if they create a scene
at the wedding?
- Stop.
- Please, sir.
Around 60 people died in Kallakurichi
after consuming bootleg liquor.
I got a call from the SP’s office,
so I sent all the men there.
Do one thing.
Have your mother’s wedding
in Chennai or Coimbatore.
- Can't rest a bit!
- Sir. Sir.
In our village, there are many women
like my mother.
To bring a change in their hearts,
I must hold my mother’s wedding
without any trouble,
- at our temple.
- Hey! Hey!
Will you shut it?
The police won’t protect you
just because you want to prove a point.
Playing rebel, are you?
Get out!
Why not, sir?
One constable?
- Just one.
- Hey!
Who the hell are you
to preach the law here?
Are you an M.P. or an M.L.A?
- Why should I protect a nobody like you?
- Why are you hitting me?
- Get out, I say!
- Sir, please. Sir.
- Throw them out!
- Go! Leave!
Give me a break!
Ezhumalai!
Valayampatti men are here to see you.
Come.
At this hour?
It's him.
He doesn't look
like he's here to talk.
Okay, get here safely.
Don’t forget the backup battery.
Okay, bye.
- Hey! Can't you hide it?
- Let's get moving!
Hey, you came here
to pay her a visit, right?
- Why the sudden wedding?
- Hey, things got really messy!
I had to act fast.
Even Mom has no idea
the wedding’s tomorrow.
- What are you saying?
- Megala called you, didn't she?
Okay, there’s a slight bruise
on Mom’s neck.
Play dumb.
Like you don’t know.
Let’s talk about it
tomorrow afternoon.
Megala would’ve surely told them
about my brother being here.
Then why hasn’t Baskar
asked about it?
That wound on his forehead…
He is keeping mum about it.
Why has Vivek come here
all of a sudden?
Dinner is ready, boys!
Ever since I heard
the wedding is tomorrow,
I don’t know why,
but I’m shaking inside.
My heart feels so heavy,
like a cart full of sugarcane.
Selvi!
Quick! I'm hungry.
- I'm hungry, Selvi.
- Come fast, Mom!
Start eating.
I'll join.
Why?
All of a sudden?
Come, let’s eat together.
He's right
When the kids were here,
there was never just one leaf
or a single plate on the floor.
I made them all
sit together for dinner.
But…
- From now on…
- Selvi.
Mom, here.
Have some.
Is this the last time
I’ll have dinner
with my sons like this?
Sorry, Mom.
I told you a bit late.
No problem.
Eat!
Will there be room for me as a mother
in the house I’m marrying into?
Will they even see me… as a mother?
Mom, the curry is just…
perfect!
Go on, eat.
- Enough, Mom!
- Mine!
You!
Here, have some.
Enough, Mom.
If they come home,
they’ll have to cook
for themselves, right?
- I'll be elsewhere…
- Mom.
Make the same potato fry tomorrow,
- but add more oil, okay?
- Hey!
Mom…
Mom, why are you crying?
What's wrong?
Don't cry, Mom.
- Don't cry, Mom.
- I don't want to go.
- I'm right here, Mom.
- I'm not going anywhere.
It's alright.
Don't cry.
- Don't worry, Mom.
- Stay with me.
I don't want this.
I don't want to go.
Don't cry, Mom.
It's alright, Mom.
We're right here.
We're just a call away.
- Please, don't cry, Mom.
- I don't want to leave you.
Instead of coming here,
we’ll just come there.
It's alright.
Don't cry.
I don't want to go.
I don't want to.
Mom.
It's time.
- Hello?
- I'm the priest's wife, sir.
They thrashed him and broke his head
to stop the wedding.
We've admitted him in the hospital.
What happened?
[busy tone]
Everybody, keep quiet.
Let Pachaperumal speak.
Whatever happens,
we're with Pacha.
Hey, we advised you so much
yesterday, and you’re still here?
If you really want this widow's hands,
do it in your town's temple.
Yes. Get out of here.
Who's the widow here?
I was alone for
the past six and a half years.
Now, she's here
to be my companion.
Not only that.
To be honest, she's the one
saving this wayward.
What?!
A woman saving a man?!
Interesting.
Come on, Baskar.
Go, bring it.
Action.
Come on. Cover the situation
from all the sides.
Fast!
Every dumbo of the village is here.
Cover them.
Ready, Ready!
Camera 4, be ready.
Yes, Kimki.
Drones shouldn't move
without my say.
Okay, sir.
- Sandhya, go live.
- Done!
Who are these people?
Why are so many of them here?
Our channel's bringing
a sensational content.
Brilliant idea! Amazing, Baskar!
Sir, your name?
He's Pacha.
Pachaperumal.
Oh, it's him?
The right to remarry,
regardless of gender,
was recognized
even during the British period.
Do you know that it's a crime
to oppose it?
- What? Crime?!
- He's pushing the mic.
- A crime?
- Yes.
You'll be locked up
for two and a half years. Know that?
Did you hear that, man?
Jail for two and a half years!
Why meddle in this?
Drone C, capture that long haired guy.
Go near him.
- Go, go!
- Yes, sir. Sure.
Look! They've even got billhooks!
- Zoom in!
- Camera 4, focus on the weapons.
Very good! Very good!
You're here to stop a remarriage
with weapons.
- That'll get you seven and a half years.
- What?!
Seven and a half years?!
Pacha is trying to get us locked up, man.
This is being telecast live.
Do you know that?
- What's that?
- Means the entire town is watching us.
Town?!
The entire world is watching us.
Our faces would be on
the wanted list now.
He's in a government job.
Leave him.
Run away, man.
Drone C, follow the hair guy.
He's moving back.
He's trying to hide behind the crowd.
Don't let him.
He'll mess up our plan.
Focus on him.
Leave my shirt, man.
How will you even hide here?
- How many liters of liquor did you get?
- Are you trying to get us arrested?
I've seen this somewhere.
Me too, man.
- She's telling that we'll get seven years.
- And this thing keeps following us.
Now I know what this is.
It's… 'that', right?
CORONA TIME
Oh, god! Please!
Don't take me.
Where did my mom go?
That's it! Super!
Great job! Awesome!
I still remember the thrashings.
- You're the carrom board guy, right?
- Yeah, man.
Oh, God!
The police is watching.
Run!
The crowd is scattering.
Put the drones on them.
Hey, stop. Don't run.
Why are you running?
Deal this Pacha.
Drone A, head toward the river.
Sandhya,
put Drone B on the live feed.
That guy doesn't even
care about his dhoti. Catch him.
Leave no one.
Just follow them.
Look! That one is showing us his rear.
Cover him.
Cover his face.
Look that friend in need
and the friend in deed. Cover them, too.
Start the vehicle.
Hold Camera 4 on this spot. Let's go!
Follow them till they reach
the village border.
Run, guys!
Pacha, you're dead.
Don't ever think of coming back.
Didn't you say that the entire
village will stand beside you?
I see no one.
Only he is here.
Ezhumalai.
Whack him, man.
Do you know anything about
cutting sugarcane?
One slash near the root.
One slash in the middle.
In the third slash, the leaf sheath
goes to the trash,
and the cane joins the load.
Someone has already done our job.
Hey, arrest him.
Hey, you've freaked
an entire police station out!
You could've told me
that you're a media person.
- What do you want from me?
- I told you yesterday.
- The wedding.
- That's why I rushed here.
I'll get them married.
Where is the bride?
This is your mom, right?
Why are you holding the garland?
It'll be heavy. Give it to me.
He's the groom, right?
It's him. I can tell.
And, where are the media people?
They were covering those guys.
Look!
Come on.
Vandhana, come fast.
Now, another problem?
Don't you get worried.
Be happy.
With this uniform,
I'll break the lock as well.
- Where's the stone?
- The priest is not here.
We're here, right?
There's no need for a priest.
Then, action!
I'll break it now.
Cut!
- Who the hell is he?
- Baskar, this is too much.
The script might be yours.
But, I'm the director.
ACTION!
APRIL 17
KALLAKURICHI
VALAYAMPATTU
EZHUMALAI AND SELVI IN REAL LIFE
AFTER A FEW MONTHS
FLEW BY…
I'm guessing you're here
for something special.
How can I help?
I'm here to look for a groom
for my daughter-in-law.
Hey! She is Megala from my village.
The marriage will definitely happen.
Are you happy?
- Baskar! Vivek!
- Hi, Dad.
- Give me your bag.
- It's fine, Dad.
- Are you guys hungry?
- Yeah.
- We'll be there soon.
Get on.
- Shall we?
- Yes.
It will be spicy, man.
Dad, Mom won't eat
until we reach.
At least you could've eaten.
But, I didn't marry her
to sit and eat alone.
It's not a big deal.
Instead of turning Mom into a stone
by calling her an idol or a goddess…
you saw her as a human,
respected her and stood by her.
That's what matters.
It was all my brother.
- Some for you.
- Dad.
We're mere knives.
Only she had the courage
to wield it.
My mom, who believed
life can begin at any age,
is truly on another level.
- Give me that.
- Here.
- Vivek, have more eggs.
- Sure.
Give one to Baskar.
Have some more potatoes.
- Eat well.
- Mom, it's amazing.
Of course.
Hey, you have payasam for dessert.
- Wow!
- Dad made it.
Subtitles by QUBE